Constance Baker Motley papers SSC.MS.00110
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, 1956-66
  The Borough of Manhattan subseries includes campaign material, press releases, the 1965 Annual report of the Borough, and subject files. The campaign material relates to Motley's campaign for re-election as President of the Borough in November 1965. The subject files are arranged alphabetically and include material related to various projects, committees, and miscellaneous social and political issues that surfaced from February 1965 to August 1966. Topics include the revitalization of Harlem; housing discrimination and tenants' rights; and a White House conference on civil rights in which Motley participated. There is also a file containing articles and letters regarding city taxi drivers accused of discriminating against blacks, including a New York Post article by Langston Hughes. For more information on Motley's activities during her term as Borough President, see SERIES IV. SPEECHES, which focuses mainly on that time period.
  The Federal District Court subseries includes subject files; clippings related to miscellaneous cases; applications for jobs received by Motley when she first assumed the judgeship; and congratulatory letters from other Southern District Judges upon her appointment to Senior status in 1986 (other congratulatory letters are filed in SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE-General). The series includes legal documents, articles, and letters reflecting both positive and negative public reaction to Motley's controversial decision in Ludtke v. Kuhn, the 1978 case in which Judge Motley ruled that Melissa Ludtkea sports writer for Time, Inc., be admitted to the New York Yankees' locker room. Another file contains both positive and negative responses to her decision regarding police protection of Vietnam war protesters in Belknap et al v. Leary (1970).
  - NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund, Inc.
    - Printed material, 1961-68, undated (includes articles about Motley, Thurgood Marshall, and Jack Greenberg) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Civil rights cases: clippings
      - University of Alabama (Autherine Lucy), 1956 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Montgomery Alabama bus boycotts, 1956; 1963 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Mississippi (miscellaneous), 1956-61 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Civil Rights Act of 1964 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Census of African American population by borough, New York City, circa, 1960s (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Petitions to withdraw from NAACP cases submitted by CBM when she assumed the Manhattan Borough Presidency, February 1966 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - New York State Advisory Council on Unemployment and Employment Insurance
    - Taxation of land values: printed material, circa, 1958-64; undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Letter of resignation and reply from Governor Nelson Rockefeller, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - New York State Senate
    - Special election and campaign for re-election: statement, questionnaires, and publicity, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Press releases, circa, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Bills, circa, 1964
    - Alcoholic beverage control law (Moreland Commission) (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
    - Animal experimentation and humane slaughter (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Domestic relations, re: religious affiliation in adoption (includes memorandum from Attorney Florynce R Kennedy) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Domestic workers (re: benefits for) (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Fire departments (anti-discrimination law) (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Labor organizations (anti-discrimination law) (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Multiple dwelling (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Police, search warrants (also known as "Stop & search bill") (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Private housing finance (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Scholar Incentive Program for High School Students (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - School finance (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - School desegregation (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Unemployment insurance for non-profit organizations (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Subjects
    - Civil Rights Action proposal, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Morningside Heights neighborhood and Columbia land deal, 1963-65 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      [see also SERIES IV. SPEECHES, 4/10/65]
    - Police brutality issue, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Borough of Manhattan
    - Campaign for re-election as President, Aug-Nov, 1965
      - General: correspondence, memoranda, notes, memorabilia (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - New York County Democratic Committee: correspondence (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Mailing lists (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Contributions (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Expenses (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Press Releases, 1965-66 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Annual Report, Borough of Manhattan, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous: notes and memoranda, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Subjects
      - Board of Ethics, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Citizens to Keep New York City Clean, 1964-65 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Columbia University Center for Research and Education in Civil Liberties, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Commission on Human Rights, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Community Planning Board, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Harlem housing legislation, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Housing and urban development, 1965-66 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing, 1964-65 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - 94th Street Armory housing and Junior High School proposal, April-May; 1965 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - Proportional representation, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Taxicabs and discrimination, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Tenants steering committee, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Udall, Stewart (report of the NYC Planning Commission on the Secretary of the Interior's visit to New York) (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - United Nations International School, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - Urban America, Inc., 1966 (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - White House Conference: "To Fulfill These Rights," 1965 (includes correspondence from Hubert Humphrey and A. Phillip Randolph) (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Federal District Court
    - Congratulatory letters from Southern District Judges re: Senior status, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Job applications (requesting position with Judge Motley), 1966 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Clippings re: miscellaneous cases, 1972-87 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Subjects
      - Belknap et al. v. Leary (police protection of war demonstrators), 1970 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Judicial Conference of Second Circuit, Whiteface Inn, Lake Placid, NY, June 30-July 2, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Ludtke v. Kuhn: legal documents and correspondence, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- SERIES IV. SPEECHES, 1963-88
  This series contains mostly typescripts of speeches written and delivered by Motley from 1963 to 1988. They are arranged chronologically and in some cases are accompanied by fliers, posters, or other printed material. Related correspondence, (invitations and responses, travel arrangements, etc.) can be found in SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE-General. The bulk of the speeches are from Motley's term as Manhattan Borough President in 1965. Recurring topics include civil rights; urban development (especially in Harlem) and neighborhood programs (such as the Henry Street Settlement); equality in education; women in politics and the legal profession; and leadership in the black community. In addition there are tributes to prominent individuals; commencement speeches; fundraising for community organizations; civic events; and papers given at panels, conferences and lecture series.
  - Women's City Club of New York, Inc., November 19, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - New York Ethical Culture Society, March 15, 1964 (Box 13)
  - "The Civil Rights Crisis," statement prepared for State Democratic Committee Campaign Schools by Senator Motley, 1964 (Box 13)
  - (untitled) "The increased pressures of the times...,", 1963 (Box 13)
  - Opening of International Flower Show, New York City, March 6, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - JOIN (Job Orientation in Neighborhoods) graduation, March 9, 1965 (Box 13)
  - National Newspaper Publishers, honoring John B. Russworm, March 12, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Ribbon-cutting ceremony, May's Department Store, March 18, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Harlem-Brooklyn Committee for Big Sisters (5th Annual Program), March 20, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Reunion of 369th Veterans Association, March 21, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Multiple Sclerosis luncheon, March 31, 1965 (Box 13)
  - New Era Club, April 9, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Morningside Community Center, April 10, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Reform Independent Democrats, April 21, 1965 (Box 13)
  - United Democrats Club/Wilheminia Adams, April 22, 1965 (Box 13)
  - UAW-AFL/CIO luncheon, April 24, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Society for the Advancement of Judaism, April 25, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Lexington Democratic Club, May 1, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Day Care Week program, May 3, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Opening of exhibit on the accomplishments of minorities in American history, at P.S. 144, May 4, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Manhattan Boro-wide Salute to Music, Hunter College, May 5, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Day Care Council of New York, May 5, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Sojourner Truth Awards luncheon, National Association of Negro Business Professional Women, May 9, 1965 (Box 13)
  - National Council of Jewish Women, May 11, 1965 (Box 13)
  - District Youth-Adult Citizenship Conference, May 17, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Women's Division of American Jewish Congress, May 17, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Puerto Rican Association of Women Voters, May 19, 1965 (Box 13)
  - League of Women Voters, May 24, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Encampment for Citizenship, May 2, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Vest Pocket Development (West Side Urban Renewal), May 27, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Riverside Country School, May 27, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Public Personnel Association Convention, June 3, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Community Planning Board (Rebuilding of Harlem) Columbia University, June 5, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Greenwich Village Association, June 8, 1965 (Box 13)
  - 55th Annual Meeting of the Urban League, June 9, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Proposed construction of a cement plant on the Harlem River, June 11, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Proposed demolition of the High School of Commerce, June 11, 1965 (Box 13)
  - P.S. 161 (International Fiesta), June 12, 1965 (Box 13)
  - East Midtown Reform Democrats Club, June 14, 1965 (Box 13)
  - East Side Chamber of Commerce, June 16, 1965 (Box 13)
  - P.S. 125 (Children's Organization for Civil Rights), June 18, 1965 (Box 13)
  - New Chelsea Reform Democrats Club, June 18, 1965 (Box 13)
  - J.H.S. 43 Graduation, June 23, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Delacorte Animated Clock dedication, June 24, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Benjamin Franklin High School graduation, June 25, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Charles Evans Hughes High School graduation, June 29, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Community Planning Board (park safety), July 13, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Opening of First Neighborhood Information and Service Center, July 20, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - National Insurance Convention, July 20, 1965 (Box 13)
  - WNYC radio broadcast, "Rebuilding Harlem,", August 9, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Convention of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference, Birmingham, AL, August 9, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Proportional Representation Campaign Committee, August 11, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Site Selection Board meeting, after vote on use of 94th St. Armory Site, August 23, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Proposal before the Board of Estimates for an Industrial Park on the Brooklyn Flatlands Site, September 24, 1965 (Box 13)
  - WLIB radio statement against industrial park in Brooklyn Flatlands, September 27, 1965 (Box 13)
  - 25th Anniversary Dinner Dance of the Vulcan Society honoring Chief Wesley Williams, Baldwin, L.I., NY, September 29, 1965 (Box 13)
  - First Borough President's Conference of Community Leaders, September 29, 1965 (Box 13)
  - WWRL radio, Harlem development, October 1, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - West Indian Veterans dance, October 2, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Acceptance of AAUW Woman of the Year, Columbia University, October 8, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Woman's day at the Church of the Master, October 10, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Transport Workers Union, October 11, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Delacorte Fountain dedication, October 11, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Liberal Party 21st Annual Dinner, October 13, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Opening of the 114th St Rehabilitation Project, October 14, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Testimonial Dinner in honor of Rev. Dr. Allen E. Claxton, Broadway (Box 13)
  - Temple Methodist Church, October 20, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Opening of the Hudson Guild Center for the Aged, October 21, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Women's Day, Victory Tabernacle Seventh-Day Christian Church, October 23, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Emmanuel AME Church fundraising banquet, October 23, 1965 (Box 13)
  - St. Phillips Church Annual Fellowship Luncheon, October 23, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Testimonial dinner for Abraham E. Kazan, 24 October 1965 (Box 13)
  - Jamaica Industrial Development Corp., October 26, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Address to City Planning Commission (revitalization between 110th and 155th Streets), October 26, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Congress of Senior Citizens Rally (advent of Medicare, etc), October 27, 1965 (Box 13)
  - WWRL radio (revitalization of Harlem), October 27, 1965 (Box 13)
  - East Side Chamber of Commerce Dinner, October 30, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Metropolitan Community Methodist Church, November 14, 1965 (Box 13)
  - National Committee For Rural Schools, November 20, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Educational Parks Conference (segregated schools), November 30, 1965 (Box 13)
  - YMCA conference, "New Horizons for Women in the Political and Social Life of the Nation,", December 2, 1965 (Box 13)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews in Philadelphia, December 2, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Orin Lehman Beth Jacob Schools Awards Presentation, December 5, 1965 (Box 13)
  - WWRL and WLIB radio (revitalization of Harlem) December 7, 1965 Committee on Civil Rights in Manhattan, circa 1965 (Box 13)
  - Dinner for Councilman J. Raymond Jones, given by the Cerberean Society, circa, 1965 (Box 13)
  - City Planning Commission at the Capital Budget Hearing, City Hall, December 15, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Christmas message at the Christmas tree lighting ceremony at City Hall, December 16, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Riker's Island, December 21, 1965 (Box 13)
  - Mayor Lindsay's inauguration (not delivered), January 1, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - New York Shakespeare Festival acquisition of "Landmark Building," the former Astor Library, January 5, 1966 (Box 13)
  - The Second Borough President's Conference of Community Leaders, YWCA, January 21, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Basic Education Classes of the Free-Employment Training Program, February 11, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Friendly Towns, affiliated with the Herald Tribune Fresh Air Fund: speech and draft, February 17, 1966 (Box 13)
  - P.S. 90 (228 West 148th St, NYC): speech and draft, February 24, 1966 (Box 13)
  - "Humanitarian of the Community Award" to Miss Lorraine D. Miller, Stuyvesant Chapter of Cancer Care at the Hotel Pierre): speech and draft, February 26, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Sisterhood of Temple Rodeph Sholom): speech and draft, February 28, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Manhattan Community Planning Boards, March 2, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Introduction of Frances Levenson (housing and inter-group relations): speech and draft, March 5, 1966 (Box 13)
  - "Education is too important to be left solely to educators....": speech and draft, March 8, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Women's Day of the Abyssinian Baptist Church: speech, draft and program, March 13, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Introduction of Corporation Counsel J. Lee Rankin, at the annual dinner of the Men's Class of the Riverside Church: speech and draft, March 15, 1966. (Box 13)
  - Speech honoring Helen Hall, Executive Director of the Henry Street Settlement, March 1966 (Box 13)
  - Remarks on receiving a Spirit of Achievement Award presented by Greater New York Chapter National Women's Division, Albert Einstein College of Medicine: speech and draft, April 20, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Plaque presentation to the Rev. Dr. Allen E. Claxton, Community Planning Board, 12, April 26, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Women's Bar Association, December 8, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Hadassah-Myrtle Wreath Award, December 14, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Presentation of the Mary McLeod Bethune Award to A. Philip Randolph, December 19, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Untitled draft (planning board meeting), circa, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Address before Columbia Law School Alumni Association, January 27, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "The Quest for a New Equality," United Church Women of Lower Middlesex County, CT, April 29, 1967 (Box 14)
  - Edward Waters College Alumni Testimonial Banquet honoring Dr. William B. Stewart, May 10, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Bennett College Symposium "The College Woman in Today's World,", October 11, 1968 (Box 14)
  - "On Meeting Our Responsibility for Providing Legal Assistance to the Poor in Civil Cases," AAUW Forum, February 22; 69 (Box 14)
  - "Separate but Equal-Reexamined," Cornell University, April 12, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Comencement Address, Saint Augustine's College, Raleigh, NC, May 25, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Award Dinner, National Conference of Christians and Jews, November 22, 1970 (Box 14)
  - "Twenty Years Later-My Personal Recollections of Brown and Some Personal Comments On Its Impact and Implementation" Third Annual Civil Rights Lectures, Center for Civil Rights, University of Notre Dame, March 21, 1974 (Box 14)
  - "Securing the Rights of the Individual in an Organized Society" The Brattleboro Forum, Brattleboro, VT, April 2, 1976 (Box 14)
  - "The Role of the Federal Courts in Establishing Justice" American Revolution Bicentennial Committee, Westport, CT, October 21, 1976 (Box 14)
  - Gate City Bar Association "Law Day '77" Atlanta, GA, May 4, 1977 (Box 14)
  - Graduate and Professional School's Convocation, Rutgers University, June 3, 1977 (Box 14)
  - Presentation of the Personal Papers of Ernest Nathan Morial to the Amistad Research Center, New Orleans, LA, April 30, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Dedication of the Shad Polier Library, June 19, 1978 (Box 14)
  - Philadelphia Area Lawyers' Wives Judicial Luncheon (25th anniversary of Supreme Court decision voiding state-sanctioned racial segregation in public education), March 24, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Women's Forum medal of achievement Yale University, May 6, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Commencement Address, Spelman College, May 20, 1979 (Box 14)
  - "The Law as an Instrument of Social Change" U. of Montana Law School, Missoula, MT, March 2, 1980 (Box 14)
  - "Prisoners' Rights-Rights of Mental Patients: Recent Developments in the Law" American Psychiatric Association Convention, San Francisco, May 7, 1980 (Box 14)
  - One-Hundredth Anniversary, Episcopal Churchwomen of Connecticut, November 9, 1980 (Box 14)
  - Women and Work Conference, Smith College, March 10, 1982 (Box 14)
    [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL-- Articles and newspaper clippings]
  - "A Nation of Litigators-The Constitution Its Sword," New York County Lawyers Annual Bar Dinner, December 9, 1982 (Box 14)
  - "The Federal Courts: The Next 100 Years," Symposium at South Carolina Law School, September 1986 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "Legal Defense Fund Award to Judge Robert L. Carter,", March 25, 1988 (Box 14)
  - Chevene Bowers King Memorial, Albany, GA, March 18-19, 1988 (Box 14)
- Ford Foundation Grant Project, Columbia University Law School, 1995; 1 boxes; 0.004 Gigabytes 114 files
  Two databases and supporting documents created as part of Ford Foundation project, 1995. The first dataase is a catalog of Motely's papers at both Columbia University and the Sophia Smith Collection. The second database is case decisions and summaries. There are also text documents containing biographical information, and case summaries (see detailed description in box 15).
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  This collection contains materials received from the donor in digital form that are not currently available online. Please consult with Special Collections staff to request access to this digital content.
  - Description of project and database files, 2 items 3 1/2 inch floppy disks (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - NAACP: index, list, and selected printouts of case summaries (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Federal District Court: selected printouts of case summaries (Box 15, Folder 3)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Biographical materials: Scrapbook, 1965-66 (Box 16)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson poster and congratulatory note from Frederick V. Seabrook, undated (Flat file folder Flat File)
  - Allen Morrison, "Top Woman Civil Rights Lawyer: Constance Baker Motley Secures Rights for Millions," Ebony, January 1963 (Flat file folder Flat File)
  - International Research Committee on Real Estate Taxation, "A Graphic Summary of Municipal Improvement and Finance as Affected by the Untaxing of Improvements and the Taxation of Land Values,", undated (Flat file folder Flat File)
- Joel Motley collection of Constance Baker Motley papers, 1934-2018; 2018-S-0057; Motley, Constance Baker; Motley, Joel; 4 linear feet 3 record cartons, 1 11x14 OS box, 1 oversize folder.
  This addition to the Constance Baker Motley papers contains the materials collected by her son, Joel Motley after her death in 2005. The collection primarily focuses on Motley's professional writing and speeches, containing Motley's judicial opinions from 1977-1997. In addition, the collection includes several annotated Supreme and District Court decisions dating from 1955-1963, as well as booklets concerning racial discrimination in education and housing. The collection also documents commemorative events in Motley's honor after her passing, such as the Constance Baker Motley symposium at Quinnipiac University in 2009.
  - SUBSERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, 1936-2018
    - Constance Baker Motley memorial mass program, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Simmie Knox portrait artist business card, approximately 1995 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Fordham University Commencement program, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Edna E. Baker Carnegie memorial mass program, 2008 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Washington Post article on Constance Baker Motley's death, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "The Story of Truth", approximately 1970 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Sandra J. McLaughlin curriculum vitae, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Chester Historical Society Annual Report, 2017-2018 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Journal magazine, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Princeton University commencement program, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Credo: a Testament of Faith in the Mission of Fisk University by L.M. Collins (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Thurgood Marshall memorial mass program, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Simpson, Thacher, & Bartlett inter-office memorandum, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Department of Justice Letter to Constance Baker Motley regarding personal data sheet, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Blank personal data sheet questionnaire, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - United States Senate letter to Constance Baker Motley regarding personal data sheet, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Typed answers to questionnaire, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Handwritten answers to questionnaire, approximately 1965 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Society of Golden Sons and Daughters of Fisk College certificate, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Gusta Lewis Troup Junior High School Diploma, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Photos, 1963-2005 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Passports, 1995, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1956-2005
      - Clippings from various newspapers, 1963-2005 (Box 17, Folder 10-11)
      - Clippings from Tuscaloosa News, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Miscellaneous clippings, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - SUBSERIES II: CORRESPONDENCE, 1950-2009